<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog</title>
    <link>https://arushirai1.github.io/personal-site/</link>
    <description>Recent content on blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://arushirai1.github.io/personal-site/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BlogPostTitle={Regression Course Reflections, The Hat Matrix and Influence}</title>
      <link>https://arushirai1.github.io/personal-site/posts/regression-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arushirai1.github.io/personal-site/posts/regression-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Reflections from my Regression course and explaining the Hat matrix and its significance in determining outliers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Third Chipy Post</title>
      <link>https://arushirai1.github.io/personal-site/posts/third-chipy-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 22:46:03 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arushirai1.github.io/personal-site/posts/third-chipy-post/</guid>
      <description>Last post I left off on getting the neighborhood regions and grocery markers on the map. This month was largely spent on getting the data set up for food desert calculations. I spent a bit of time on the theoretical aspect to create the algorithm. However, in practice doing a step like projections to XY coordinates took a long time.
This blog post, I’m breaking down the methodology/theory of determining a food desert region and then I will be discussing the progress in my application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second Chipy Post</title>
      <link>https://arushirai1.github.io/personal-site/posts/second-chipy-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 17:30:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arushirai1.github.io/personal-site/posts/second-chipy-post/</guid>
      <description>Link to Github Link to Heroku Website
I first started off by finding another dataset with grocery stores in Chicago because the first one was not all of the grocery stores. Then, I used Grocery Stores - 2013, however, this has convinience stores and liquor stores counting as Grocery stores. After searching for more, I decided to settle on this dataset for now since I needed to start coding. My first goal was loading the dataset as markers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chipy First Post</title>
      <link>https://arushirai1.github.io/personal-site/posts/chipy-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2019 14:10:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arushirai1.github.io/personal-site/posts/chipy-first-post/</guid>
      <description>I joined the Chipy mentorship program in hopes of expanding my Python abilities and learning better methods of writing Python code. I really wanted to meet like-minded people and be in the company of people working towards similar goals.
The first challenge was figuring out my project and the scope of it. I have been closely studying the food desert crisis in the Southside and the abundance of fast food and dearth of fresh produce.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hpc Research</title>
      <link>https://arushirai1.github.io/personal-site/posts/hpc-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2017 14:18:24 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://arushirai1.github.io/personal-site/posts/hpc-research/</guid>
      <description>I have always been interested in learning about cutting edge technologies and enjoy applying logic to solve problems. During the summer and fall of 2017, I learned about high performance computing and modified CQSim, the HPC queue simulator.
Project Learning and Exploring Cobalt &amp;ndash; the HPC Job Management Suite
Weekly Updates Update One (7-17-17) I spent this week getting familiar with Cobalt&amp;rsquo;s administrative and user commands. I have almost finished installing the simulation environment on a CentOS 6.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>